let chem  = [
  {
    question: `Mendelev periodic table was arranged in order of their `,
    options:["Atomic numbers",
    "Molecular shapes",
    "Atomic mass",
    `Orbital structire`],
    answer: "Atomic mass",
  },
  {
    question: `Which of the following decreases across the period of the
    periodic table?`,
    options: ["Atomic size",
    "Electron affinity",
    `Electronegativity`, 
    `Inert tendencies`],
    answer: "Atomic size",
  },
  {
    question: `Which of the following compound is insoluble in water?`,
    options:
    [`MgO`,
    `P<sub>4</sub>O<sub>10</sub>`,
    `K<sub>2</sub>O`,
    `N<sub>2</sub>O<sub>3</sub>`],
    answer: `MgO`,
  },
  {
    question: `From the balanced equation, what is the value of X?<br>
    Pb(NO<sub>3</sub>)<sub>2</sub>(aq) + XNaCl(aq) ➞  PbCl<sub>2</sub>(s) +
    2NaNO<sub>3</sub>(aq) ?`,
    options: ["1","2","3","4"],
    answer: "2",
  },
  {
    question:`What mass of anhydrous sodium trioxocarbonate(IV),
    Na<sub>2</sub>CO<sub>3</sub>, is present in 500 cm<sup>3</sup> of 0.1 mol
    dm<sup>-3</sup> Na<sub>2</sub>CO<sub>3</sub> solution? 
    [Na = 23, C = 12, O = 16]
    `,
    options:["10.6 g","212 g", "5.3 g", "106 g"],
    answer: "5.3 g",
  },
  {
    question: `Flow of current in electrolytes is due to the movement of `,
    options:["electrons","holes and electrons","ions","charges"],
    answer: "ions",
  },
  {
    question: ` What quantity of electricity is consumed when 10 Amperes was
    consumed in 1 hour during electrolysis?`,
    options: ["36 kC", "3600 C","7200 C", "72 kC"],
    answer: "36 kC",
  },
  {
    question: `The standard electrode potential value of pure hydrogen at all temperature
    is? `,
    options: ["1 V","2 V","0 V","0.5 V"],
    answer: "0 V",
  },
  {
    question: `The minimum or critical amount of energy required before a
    chemical reaction could occur is called `,
    options:["Reaction energy",
    "Effective collision", 
    `Activation energy`,
    `activated complex`],
    answer: `Activation energy`,
  },
  {
    question:`Which is the most abundant noble gas in nature?`,
    options:["Neon","Radon","Helium","Argon"],
    answer: "Argon",
  },
  {
    question:`What chemical process is represented by the following equation?<br> 
     4Fe(s) + 3O<sub>2</sub>(g) +2xH<sub>2</sub>(l)
     ➞2Fe<sub>2</sub>O<sub>3</sub>.xH<sub>2</sub>O(s)`,
     options:["Combustion","Oxidation",'Hydration',"Rusting"],
     answer: "Rusting",
  },
  {
    question:`Basic nuclear radiation was discovered by `,
    options:["Becquerel","Marie Curie","Geiger Muller","Marsden"],
    answer: "Becquerel",
  },
  {
    question: `Which isotope of Hydrogen is commonly referred to as heavy
    hydrogen?`,
    options:["Protium","Deuterium","Tritium","Basic water"],
    answer: "Deuterium",
  },
  {
    question: `Which of the following is an alkaline gas?`,
    options:[`NO<sub>2</sub>`,`NH<sub>3</sub>`,`N<sub>2</sub>O`,
    `N<sub>2</sub>O<sub>4</sub>`],
    answer: `NH<sub>3</sub>`,
  },
  {
    question:`The partial pressure of oxygen in a sample of air is 452mm Hg and
    the total pressure is 780mm Hg. What is the mole fraction of oxygen?`,
    options: [`0.203`,"0.579","2.030","5.790"],
    answer: '0.579',
  },
  {
    question:`What is the name of the chemical compound CuCO<sub>3</sub>?`,
    options:[`Copper(III)carbonate`,
    `Copper(II)carbonate`,
    "Copper(I)carbonate",
    "Copper"],
    answer:"Copper(II)carbonate",
  },
  {
    question:`The enzyme that converts glucose to ethyl alcohol is ?`,
    options:["Maltase","Zymase","Diatase","Invertase"],
    answer: "Zymase",
  },
  {
    question:`Which of the following is a non-metal that remains a liquid at
    room temperature?`,
    options:["Mercury","Chlorine","Bromine","Phosphorus"],
    answer: "Bromine",
  },
  {
    question:`A phenomenom where a substance transit from solid state to gaseous
    state without the intermediate liquid state is called?`,
    options:["Radiation","Sublimation","Evaporation","Diffusion"],
    answer: "Sublimation",
  },
  {
    question:`The process of extracting a metal from its ore is called?`,
    options:["Metallurgy","Extraction","Prospecting","Metal mining"],
    answer:"Metallurgy",
  },
  {
    question:`The molar enthalpy change accompanying  the removal of an electron
    from a gas phase atom or ion in its ground state is called?  `,
    options:["Electron gain enthalpy",
    "Ionization enthalpy",
    `Enthalpy change`,
    "Enthalpic gas removal"],
    answer: "Ionization enthalpy",
  },
  {
    question:`The process by which a salt loses its water of crystallization to
    the atmosphere on exposure is called?`,
    options:["Efflorescence","Deliquescence",`Effervescence`,`Flourescence`],
    answer: "Efflorescence",
  },
  {
    question:`The weakest atttactive force that can be observed between two molecules
    is ?`,
    options:["Ionic","Covalent","Co-ordinate covalent","Vander waals"],
    answer: "Vander waals",
  },
  {
    question:`Cathode rays cause an object placed  behind a perforated anode to
    cast a shadow on the screen. This observation shows that the rays `,
    options:[`Are positively charged`,
    `Are negatively charged`,
    `Have mass`,
    `travel in straight lines`],
    answer: "travel in straight lines",
  },
  {
    question:`Which of the following metal burns with brick red flame?`,
    options:["Pb","Ca","Na","Mg"],
    answer:"Ca",
  },
  {
    question:`P<sub>1</sub>V<sub>1</sub> = P<sub>2</sub>V<sub>2</sub>
    mathematically summarizes `,
    options:["Charles' law","Boyles' law","Graham's law","Avogadro's law"],
    answer:"Boyles' law",
  },
  {
    question:`A fixed mass of gas occupies a volume of 92cm<sup>3</sup> at
    3<sup>o</sup>C. What will be its volume at 18<sup>o</sup>C if the pressure
    remain constant? `,
    options:["15.3cm<sup>3</sup>",`87.3cm<sup>3</sup>`,`2.0cm<sup>3</sup>`,`97.0cm<sup>3</sup>`],
    answer: `97.0cm<sup>3</sup>`,
  },
  {
    question:`What volume of 0.5 mol/dm<sup>3</sup> H<sub>2</sub>SO<sub>4</sub> will exactly neutralize 20cm<sup>3</sup> of
    0.1 mol/dm<sup>3</sup> NaOH solution?`,
    options:[`2.0cm<sup>3</sup>`,`5.0cm<sup>3</sup>`,`6.8cm<sup>3</sup>`,`8.3cm<sup>3</sup>`],
    answer:`2.0cm<sup>3</sup>`,
  },
  {
    question:`A compound contains 40.0% carbon, 6.7% hydrogen and 53.3% oxygen.
    If the molar mass of the compound is 180, find the molecular formular [H=1,
    C=12, O=16]`,
    options:[`CH<sub>2</sub>O`,
    `C<sub>3</sub>H<sub>6</sub>O<sub>3</sub>`,
    `C<sub>6</sub>H<sub>12</sub>O<sub>6</sub>`,
    `C<sub>6</sub>H<sub>12</sub>O<sub>3</sub>`],
    answer:`C<sub>6</sub>H<sub>12</sub>O<sub>6</sub>`,
  },
	{
		question:`How many orbitals are in the d-subshell ?`,
		options:["1","3","5","7"],
		answer:"3",
	},
	{
		question:`An element X has isotopic masses of 6 and 7. If the relative abundance is 1 to 12.5 respectively, what is the relative atomic mass of X?`,
		options:["6.0","6.1","6.9","7.0"],
		answer:"6.9",
	},
	{
		question:`An element X has electronic configuration 1s<sup>2</sup>2s<sup>2</sup>2p<sup>6</sup>3s<sup>2</sup>3p<sup>6</sup>4s<sup>2</sup>. To which group of the periodic table does X belong?`,
		options:["I","II","III","IV"],
		answer:"II",
	},
	{
		question:`The atomic numbers of elements X and Y are 20 and 17 respectively. Which of the following compounds is likely to be formed by the combination of the two elements?`,
		options:["XY","XY<sub>2</sub>","XY<sub>3</sub>","X<sub>2</sub>Y"],
		answer:"XY<sub>2</sub>",
	},
	{
		question:`Consider the reaction<br> H<sup>+</sup>(aq) + OH<sup>-</sup>(aq) ➞ H<sub>2</sub>O(l).<br> The energy change taking place in the reaction above is enthalpy of `,
		options:["hydration","formation","neutralization","solution"],
		answer:"neutralization",
	},
	{
		question:`Which of the following equations represents a substitution reaction?`,
		options:[`C<sub>4</sub>H<sub>10</sub> + Cl<sub>2</sub> ➞ C<sub>4</sub>H<sub>9</sub>Cl + HCl`,
			`C<sub>2</sub>H<sub>4</sub> + HCl ➞ C<sub>2</sub>H<sub>5</sub>Cl`,
			`C<sub>2</sub>H<sub>2</sub> + 2H<sub>2</sub> ➞ C<sub>2</sub>H<sub>6</sub>`,
			`C<sub>3</sub>H<sub>4</sub> + 4O<sub>2</sub> ➞ 3CO<sub>2</sub> + 2HCl`],
		answer:`C<sub>4</sub>H<sub>10</sub> + Cl<sub>2</sub> ➞ C<sub>4</sub>H<sub>9</sub>Cl + HCl`,
	},
	{
		question:`Which of the following compounds is an alkanoate?`,
		options:[`CH<sub>3</sub>COOH`,
			`CH<sub>3</sub>COOCH<sub>3</sub>`,
			`CH<sub>3</sub>CH<sub>2</sub>OH`,
			`CH<sub>3</sub>CH<sub>2</sub>COOH`],
		answer:`CH<sub>3</sub>COOCH<sub>3</sub>`,
	},
	{
		question:`What is the percentage composition of oxygen in K<sub>2</sub>Cr<sub>2</sub>O<sub>7</sub>? [K = 39; Cr = 52; 0 = 16]`,
		options:["14.20%","26.53%","35.37%","38.09%"],
		answer:`38.09%`,
	},
	{
		question:`Consider the reaction represented by the equation: ca(OH)<sub>2</sub><sub>(aq)</sub> + CO<sub>2</sub><sub>(g)</sub> ➞ CaCO<sub>3</sub><sub>(s)</sub> + H<sub>2</sub>O<sub>(l)</sub>. CO<sub>2</sub> acts as `,
		options:[`an acidic oxide`,
			`an oxidizing agent`,
			`a basic oxide`,
			`a dehydrating agent`],
		answer:`an acidic oxide`,
	},
	{
		question:`What product is formed at the cathode during the electrolysis of concentrated sodium chloride solution using carbon electrodes?`,
		options:["Chlorine","Hydrogen","Oxygen","Sodium"],
		answer:"Hydrogen",
	},
	{
		question:`What is the empirical formula of a hydrocarbon containing 0.08 moles of carbon and 0.32 moles of hydrogen?`,
		options:[`CH<sub>2</sub>`,`CH<sub>3</sub>`,
			`CH<sub>4</sub>`,`C<sub>2</sub>H<sub>4</sub>`],
			answer:`CH<sub>4</sub>`,
	},
	{
		question:`Alkenes undergoes the following reactions except `,
		options:["addition","hydration","polymerization","substitution"],
		answer:"substitution",
	},
	{
		question:`Glucose reduces Fehling's solution on warming to `,
		options:["copper(I)oxide","copper(II)oxide","copper(I)chloride","copper(II)chloride"],
		answer:"copper(I)oxide",
	},
	{
		question:`Which of the following instrument is used in detecting the presence of radiation?`,
		options:["Cathode ray tube",
			"Geiger-Muller counter",
			"Mass spectrometer",
			"X-ray tube"],
		answer:"Geiger-Muller counter",
	},
	{
		question:`Which of the following elements is diatomic?`,
		options:["Sodium","Oxygen","Iron","Neon"],
		answer:`Oxygen`,
	},
	{
		question:`The gas law which describes the relationship between volume and temperature is `,
		options:["Boyle's law","Charles' law","Dalton's law","Graham's law"],
		answer:"Charles' law",
	},
	{
		question:`When heat is absorbed during a chemical reaction, the reaction is said to be `,
		options:["endothermic","adiabatic","exothermic","isothermal"],
		answer:"endothermic",
	},
	{
		question:`Which of the following variables is a measure of the average kinetic energy of the molecule of a gas?`,
		options:["Density","Pressure","Temperature","Volume"],
		answer:"Temperature",
	},
	{
		question:`The following factors affect the solubility of a solid in a given solvent except `,
		options:[`nature of solute`,
			`nature of solvent`,
			`pressure`,
			`temperature`],
		answer:`pressure`,
	},
	{
		question:`Which of the following organic compounds would decolourize bromine water?`,
		options:["Benzene","Cyclobutane","Hexane","Pentane"],
		answer:"Benzene",
	},
	{
		question:`Bronze is a mixture of `,
		options:["Cu and Mg",
			"Cu and Sn",
			"Cu and Zn",
			"Cu and Pb"],
		answer:"Cu and Sn",
	},

  ];
  console.log(`chem=${chem.length}`);
chem.sort((a,b)=>Math.random() - 0.5);
    for(let item of chem){
      if(!(item.options.includes("All of the above") ||
      item.options.includes("None of the above")))item.options.sort((a,b)=>Math.random()-0.5);
    };
export {chem as default};

